Frederick D. Patterson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1909-1988 (Box 6-32)
  - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala.
    - Printed material
      - "A Black Institution Pioneering Adult Education: Tuskegee Institute Past and Present, 1881-1973," doctoral dissertation by Velma L. Blackwell, 1973
      - The Changing Status of Southern Agriculture, 1972
      - Low Cash Cost Housing, 1950
      - Report of the Tuskegee Institute Task Force on its Visit to the Republic of South Africa, 1974
      - Rural America and Its People: The Forgotten Area and the Forgotten Species, 1978
      - Tuskegee in Indonesia, undated
      - Tuskegee Institute: The First Fifty Years, by Anson Phelps Stokes, 1931
      - Miscellaneous printed items, 1909-1983, undated, (2 folders)
    - Punch, Pauline and Vernon, 1951-1972 (Box 31)
    - School of Veterinary Medicine
      - Architectural plans, 1974
      - Correspondence, 1943-1982, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous items, 1970, undated
      - Newsletters, 1974-1986
      - Printed materials, 1971-1977, (3 folders)
    - Southern Observer, Tuskegee Institute
      - Articles by Patterson, 1959, undated
      - Correspondence, 1959
      - Notes, 1958-1959, undated
    - Tuskegee Institute National Historical Park, 1972
    - Voting rights in Tuskegee, Ala., circa 1940s, typescript, undated
  - United Methodist Church, Black College Fund, 1973-1984, undated (Box 32)
  - United Negro College Fund
    - Correspondence, 1974-1988, undated
    - Oral history interview with Patterson
      - Correspondence, 1980-1982
      - Transcript, 1981
    - Printed materials, 1973-1983
    - Thirtieth anniversary dinner, 1974
  - Wilson-Clark Institutional Services, 1974
- Clippings File, 1939-1981 (Box 33-37)
  Newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and articles culled from academic journals and popular magazines. Also included are a number of draft and printed copies of Patterson's writings and speeches located primarily under the headings "Authors" and "Frederick D. Patterson" and scattered elsewhere in the series under various topics. Patterson's original subject classification scheme has largely been maintained.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically first by broad subject headings and then narrower ones. A list of the subheadings with their assigned numerical classifications is located at the beginning of the first folder of each broad heading. Also, a master index is located in the first folder of the series. Items in the "Authors" and "Public Figures" folders are not filed by the original classification number but have been rearranged alphabetically by name. Similarly, the "Frederick D. Patterson" file under the "Authors" heading has been rearranged so that the materials are filed chronologically.
  - Index (Box 33)
  - African affairs, 1949-1976
  - Authors, 1942-1979
    - "A-O" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Patterson, Frederick D. See also Container 35, same heading; Container 39, Articles by Patterson; and Container 41, Speeches and writings by Patterson
      - 1945-1963, (3 folders)
      - 1967-1976, (3 folders) (Box 34)
    - "P-W" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Board memberships, 1952-1957, (2 folders)
  - Democracy, 1949-1964
  - Educational institutions, 1945-1976, (2 folders)
  - Foundations, 1948-1981, (2 folders) (Box 35)
  - Higher education, 1948-1962
  - National affairs, 1951-1952, undated
  - Negroes, 1949
  - Patterson, Frederick D., 1949-1976 See also Container 33, same heading; and Container 40, Clippings about Patterson, (2 folders)
  - Philanthropy, 1950-1977
  - Public figures, 1948-1975, (4 folders)
  - Red Cross, 1950-1951 (Box 36)
  - Regionalism, 1949-1955
  - Religion, undated
  - The South, 1939-1965, (5 folders)
  - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala., 1948-1973, (6 folders)
  - United Negro College Fund, 1948-1968, (3 folders) (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1944-1967, (5 folders)
- Miscellany, 1861-1988 (Box 38-41)
  Draft and printed copies of speeches and writings, personal clippings, printed materials, notes, land and financial documents, biographical materials, certificates and awards, and assorted memorabilia.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic, name of organization, or type of material.
  - Address books, [ 1950-1964? ] (Box 38)
  - Biographical materials
    - Materials related to memoirs, Chronicles of Faith
      - Correspondence, 1985-1988
      - Notes, drafts, etc., undated
    - Résumés and related items, 1935-1988
  - Certificates, 1923-1987
  - Financial documents, 1938-1971
  - Funeral services for Patterson, 1988
  - Identification and calling cards, 1953-1982, undated
  - Invitations, 1957-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Land and pension documents, 1861-1951
  - Miscellaneous items, 1959-1979, undated
  - Notes and unidentified drafts, 1959-1981, undated, (5 folders)
  - Printed material (Box 40)
    - Articles by Patterson, 1943-1975, undated See also Container 33, Patterson, Frederick D.; and Container 41, Speeches and writings by Patterson
    - Awards and memorial publications, 1953-1987
    - Clippings about Patterson, 1935, 1946-1988, undated See also Container 33, Patterson, Frederick D., (9 folders)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1940-1985
    - Programs, 1953-1986 (Box 41)
  - Signs and Services Co., 1966-1973
  - Speeches and writings by Patterson
    - Black colleges, 1959-1979, undated
    - College speeches, 1963-1984
    - Eulogies for Black leaders, 1971-1977
    - Letters to editors, 1963-1987
    - Miscellaneous items, 1972-1982, undated
    - "Personal notes," 1963-1968
    - "Spirit of Moton," undated
    - Tuskegee Institute, Tuskegee, Ala., 1935-1983, (2 folders)
    - United Negro College Fund, 1963-1985, undated
  - Telegrams, 1956-1979